# UMASHANKAR

Address·Flat no 202-B, Sankalp Residency, Kokar, Ranchi-834001 (Jharkhand)

Email: - shankar.uma8609@gmail.com, umashankar8609@yahoo.com

Contact: - +91-9304889312, 7050237638

## ABOUT MYSELF

I'm Kind of a person who is confident enough towards all my abilities to produce an efficacious result. I'm Accounting Specialist with a work experience of more than eight years. On the other hand, I am well prepared for the worst situation. I wish to be a part of an organization which can effectively recognize my caliber and thus enriching me with a cherished experience. I am a kind of person whose prior motive is self-development adding to it believe in learning even though it's not a direct requirement of the job.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### FROM: MARCH 2020 TO PRESENT

## ACCOUNTANT, HINDUSTAN AGRO PRODUCTS (MFG. OF PARROT SPICES)

- Manage Accounting Activities to ensure Compliance with Accounting Principles, polices and External Audits
- Preparing of Taxation workings (GST, TDS and TCS) and Internal Auditing according to the
  policies of the Department.
- Physical Verification of Company's Inventory Assets (Stock Audits)
- Analyze Balance Sheet, Profit and Loss and Preparing Financial Statements
- Handling Cash Expenses and Preparing Expenditure Statements

#### FROMAPRIL 2017TO MARCH 2020

### EXECUTIVE ACCOUNTS, HILIFE RETAIL AND FASHION LLP (NUCLEUS MALL, RANCHI)

- Recording All Financial Transactions, Accounts Payable, Receivables and Internal Auditing of Books.
- Preparing of Taxation workings (GST, TDS and TCS) and Internal Auditing according to the
  policies of the Department.
- Physical Verification of Company's Inventory Assets (Stock Audits)
- Banking Works

#### FROM NOV 2013 TO MARCH 2017

## JR. ACCOUNTANT, INDIGO CATERING AND SERVICES PVT. LTD

- Recording All Financial Transactions, Accounts Payable, and Receivables.
- Internal Auditing of Books of Accounts with the Accounts Principles.
- Banking Works

# **EDUCATION**

YEAR: 2017

BBA, SIKKIM MANIPAL UNIVERSITY, RANCHI

GPA: - Grade A

**YEAR: 2013** 

INTERMEDIATE, NRI ACADEMY, ANDHRA PRADESH

GPA: - 81%

**YEAR: 2010** 

MATRICULATION, STAR INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL, RANCHI

GPA: - 59%

## **SKILLS**

• Highly Expertise in the Field of Accountancy.

- Expertise in Budgeting and Financial Reporting.
- Expertise in Accounts Payable and Receivables
- Expertise in Taxations (Workings, Reconciling and Filings)
- Experienced in working Software (GST, Income Tax, E-Payments, E-Invoicing, E-Way Billings Tally ERP and Prime, MS Excel, Word)
- Typing Skills-Intermediary

# PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth:	15 <sup>th</sup> July 1993
Nationality:	Indian
Religion:	Hindu
Languages Known:	English, Hindi and Telugu
Hobbies:	Reading Books, Listening Music, Travelling, Cooking, etc.
Address:	Flatno202-B,SankalpResidency,KokarRanchi- 834001(Jharkhand)

## **DECLARATION**

I HEREBY SOLEMNLY AND SINCERELY AFFIRM THAT THE ABOVE INFORMATION FURNISHED BY ME IS TRUE FOR THE BEST OF MY KNOWLEDGE AND BELIEF.

PLACE: RANCHI

DATE: 06-02-2023 UMA SHANKAR